(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
開け放した窓に
To the window I opened wide
廻る乱舞のディープスカイ
The dancing deep sky is spinning
AH 仰いで...
AH Looking up...
繰り返す日々に
To the days that keep repeating
何の意味があるの
What meaning do they have?
AH 叫んで...
AH Screaming...
飛び出す GO
Fly out, GO
履き潰したロッキンシューズ
Rockin' shoes worn down
跳ね上げるパドル
Kicking up the puddles
FLASHBACK 君の FACE
Flashback to your face
I REMEMBER
あの虹を渡って
Crossing that rainbow
あの朝に帰りたい
I want to return to that morning
あの夢を並べて
Lining up those dreams
二人歩いた GLAMOROUS SKY
The GLAMOROUS SKY we walked under together
明け渡した愛に
To the love I surrendered
何の価値もないの
Has no value at all
AH 嘆いて...
AH Mourning...
吐き出す GO
Spit it out, GO
飲み干したロックンロール
Gulping down rock 'n' roll
息上がるバトル
A breath-taking battle
FLASHBACK 君の FACE
Flashback to your face
I REMEMBER
あの虹を渡って
Crossing that rainbow
あの雲に乗りたい
I want to ride that cloud
この胸に奏でる
Playing in this heart
あの...
That...
その夢を
That dream...
繋ぎ止めて
...hold onto it tight.
二人歩こう GLAMOROUS SKY
Let's walk together, GLAMOROUS SKY.
Hummm... GLAMOROUS SKY
眠れないよ...
I can't sleep...
Monday 待って Tuesday 待って
Wait for Monday, wait for Tuesday.
Wednesday 行き場のない
Wednesday, with nowhere to go...
Friday Saturday
七色 Every day
...seven-colored Every day.
闇雲に消える雲
Clouds disappearing blindly.
応えて 僕の声に
Answer to my voice.
あの雲を払って
Clear away those clouds,
君の未来照らしたい
and I want to light up your future.
この夢を抱えて
Holding this dream,
二人歩こう GLAMOROUS SKY
let's walk together, GLAMOROUS SKY.
あの虹を渡って
Crossing that rainbow,
あの空に帰りたい
I want to return to that sky.
あの夢を並べて
Lining up those dreams,
二人歩こう GLAMOROUS SKY
let's walk together, GLAMOROUS SKY.
GLAMOROUS SKY
裏路地の真ん中で
In the middle of a back alley,
慣れない景色と好かない匂いに
by unfamiliar sights and smells I dislike,
私は覆われて
I'm being covered,
染まっていくんでしょ
and I'm being dyed, right?
私は怖がりで 知らないことには手を付けず
I'm a coward, and I don't touch things I don't know.
誰かがやって来て毒味をするまで待っていた
I waited until someone came and tasted it for poison.
すること単純でマニュアル通りの生活を
Leading a life by the manual with simple things to do,
来る日も淡々と過ごしていた
I spent every day indifferently.
そういやさ そういやさ 昨日の私もこうだった
Come to think of it, I was like this yesterday, too.
そういやさ そういやさ
Come to think of it, come to think of it.
弱い音を吐いている 薄っぺらい人間です
I'm whining, a shallow person.
一歩前に出るのはやめておきます
I'll refrain from taking a step forward.
絡まれたくはないからさ
Since I don't want to get involved.
描いた理想像に
In the ideal I envisioned,
現実味がないから
there's no sense of reality,
近づけないよう生きてきます
so I'll live without getting close to it.
明日も同じよう過ごしときます
I'll spend tomorrow the same way.
路地裏の真ん中で
In the middle of a back alley,
いつもの夕日を薄目で眺めて
looking at the usual sunset with narrowed eyes,
胸の内で呟いた「いつもって何時頃だろ」
I whispered in my heart, 'What time is "usual" anyway?'
そういやさ そういやさ 昨日の夕飯これだった
Come to think of it, this was yesterday's dinner, too.
そういやさ そういやさ
Come to think of it, come to think of it.
臆病で切りが悪い 意気地なし人間です
Cowardly and indecisive, a spineless person.
後ろに下がって逃げときます
I'll step back and run away.
目立ちたくなんかないからさ
Since I don't want to stand out or anything.
描いた理想像に
In the ideal I envisioned,
現実味がないから
there's no sense of reality,
近づけないよう生きてきます
so I'll live without getting close to it.
明日も同じよう過ごしときます
I'll spend tomorrow the same way.
弱い音を吐いている 薄っぺらい人間です
I'm whining, a shallow person.
一歩前に出るのはやめておきます
I'll refrain from taking a step forward.
絡まれたくはないからさ
Since I don't want to get involved.
溜息ばかりさ 刺激足りないの
Just constant sighs, not enough excitement.
けどそう上手くいかないけどさ 試しにちゃんと生きてみよう
But it doesn't go that well, so let's try to live properly for once.
あぁ 決まった言葉 垂れてまたヒューマン
Ah, just another human, spitting out set phrases
ちょっとステキな 晒しもんね
What a lovely public spectacle you are
明日 命 眺めて 全てを無視した
Gazing at life tomorrow, ignoring everything else
額縁の中で 1000年生きてるのさ
I'm living for 1000 years inside a picture frame
昔々 偉い人が 石に文字彫って祈って
Once upon a time, a great person carved letters into stone and prayed
気の狂った 誰かが ホワイトを塗りたくった
Then someone out of their mind smeared it all over with white
ガラクタの上で くどいプロポーズを待って
Waiting for a tedious proposal atop a pile of junk
熱い口づけを 交わすとき鳴り響くクラクション
The car horn blares right as we share a passionate kiss
狂ったフリでごまかしてこうぜ
Let's keep fooling around by acting crazy
骨も残らぬパパママよ
Oh Mom and Dad, of whom not even bones remain
らったった口ずさんだ歌ののろい
Rat-ta-ta, the curse of the song I hummed
愛たくて 祭り上げては落としたヒューマン
Wanting to meet, humans who built me up only to drop me
ちょっと皮肉なオキシモロンね
Quite the ironic oxymoron, isn't it?
はずのはずに構えて全てを無視した
Ready for what was meant to be, ignoring everything else
あなたの気持ちが 1000年生きてるのさ
Your feelings are living for 1000 years
左利きの直し方も 消えない傷の抉り方も
How to fix being left-handed, how to gouge an unhealing wound
今日って感情の消し方も忘れたいし
I even want to forget how to erase today's emotions
進むか 退くか 分からないが
I don't know whether to move forward or retreat
顔も見られず殺せるらしい
But apparently, you can kill without even looking at a face
あばら屋の生活は 思い出すだけ無駄らしい
Living in a shack, it's apparently a waste just to remember
狂ったフリでごまかしてこうぜ
Let's keep fooling around by acting crazy
ちょっと笑える話をしよう
Let's tell a somewhat funny story
アハハ泣き晴らしたあの人はもう お別れで
Ah-ha-ha, that person with swollen eyes has already said goodbye
曲がって歩いて転んだヒューマン
A human who walked crooked and fell down
ちょっと皮肉なアディショナルタイム
A somewhat ironic additional time
あなたの気持ちに懸けてみたいのさ
I want to bet on your feelings
一生このまま 一本の皮一枚で繋がれた奴隷か？
Will you be a slave forever, bound by a single thread of skin?
喉元に噛み付く牙はまだあるかい？
Do you still have fangs to bite into the throat?
残り時間の少ないヒューマン 見ててあげる 楽しませて
Human with little time left, I'll watch you. Entertain me.
生きと息で生きて 何かを創ったら
Live through life and breath, and if you create something
あなたの気持ちが 1000年生きられるかも しれないから
Maybe your feelings can live for 1000 years, you never know
みんなー！ありがとう、聴いてくれて！
Everyone! Thank you for listening!
そして1周年記念ライブに来てくれて、ありがとうございます！
And thank you so much for coming to my 1st anniversary live!
1曲目はGLAMOROUS SKYで、これは生で歌ったので、緊張で声がプルップルでしたね。
The first song was GLAMOROUS SKY. I sang it live, and my voice was all shaky from nervousness.
信じられないくらい震えてました。びっくりしました。リハと全然違いました。
I was shaking unbelievably. I was so surprised. It was totally different from the rehearsal.
そしてですね、ヨワネハキ、続いて1000年生きてる、この2曲はですね、すごくあの、演出にこだわりたいなと思っていて、
And then, for the next two songs, Yowanekihaki and 1000-nen Ikiteru, I really wanted to focus on the production.
今回かなりメッセージ性を入れた3曲の構成にしたので、ちょっとね、色々見てほしいなーって思いますね。
I made this setlist of three songs with a strong message, so I really want you to take it all in.
特に1000年生きてるはね、あの、非常に、もうこれがしたいです！って無理を言って、クリエイターさんが「やります」って言ってくれて、
Especially for 1000-nen Ikiteru, I asked for a lot, saying "I really want to do this!" and the creators agreed to do it.
「え、本当ですか？」「やります」ってなって、「え、もう、お願いします」って言って、
"Really?" "Yes." "Oh, then please do!" I said.
「え、でも、でも結構難しそうだけどな、大丈夫かな？」と思ったら、あの本番届いたら、「え、良すぎだろ！」ってなって、「な、なんだこれ！」ってなって、
I was worried if it would be okay since it seemed difficult, but when the final version arrived, I was like "This is too good! What is this?!"
めちゃくちゃ良くできました。はい。あのね、事前に言ってたこちらが、あの、引っ張られてやってた、こちらですね。はい。
It turned out so well. Yes. And here is the part I mentioned before, where I was being pulled along. Yes.
また裏話とかでも話せたらなーと思います。そして、今日のハッシュタグなんですけど、こちらです、
I hope to talk more about behind-the-scenes stories later. And today's hashtag is this one,
#沙花叉クロヱ1周年記念ライブ こちらの方をつけて、みんなの応援をトレンドに響かせてもらえればと、思います！よろしくお願いします！
#SakamataChloe1stAnniversaryLive. Please use this and let everyone's support echo in the trends! Thank you!
よかったです...
I'm glad to hear that...
ろしくお願いします。
Thank you very much.
そして、えー、次の曲はですね...
And, um, the next song is...
沙花叉がずっと懸念していた、めちゃめちゃ息継ぎのなく...
One that Sakamata has been worried about, with absolutely no breaks for breathing...
そしてダンスもね、ちょっと激しめの間奏がある曲なんですが...
And the dancing too, there's a somewhat intense instrumental break...
頑張って挑みますので、聴いてもらえればと思います。
I'll do my best with it, so I hope you'll listen.
それでは聴いてください。みんなありがとう。見えてるよ。
Please listen to it. Thank you everyone. I can see you.
みんな聴いてください。
Everyone, please listen.
ストリーミングハート。
Streaming Heart.
あるがままを言えそうにない　どうか探して見せて
It seems I can't say it as it is, please find it and show me
嘘と本音の間　うまく隠しといたんで
Between lies and true feelings, I've hidden it well
それじゃダメなというしで　二人になればハッピー
Saying that's no good, being together makes us happy
そのうち一人が嫌で　一人がいいとか言って
Soon one will be hated, and saying it's better to be alone
肯定仕様もない感情の　行き先はどこでしょう
Where is the destination for these emotions that can't be affirmed
ボロボロになった台所に　また酸素を見つけたんだ
In the worn-out kitchen, I found oxygen again
弱虫だね
What a coward
落ちることが　心地よくてさあ
Falling feels so good, now
アイマイにしたいのさ　好きでいたって歪んでいく内緒
I want to make it ambiguous, even if I like you, the secret will warp
アイマイにしたいのさ　嫌いになってしまったら大成功
I want to make it ambiguous, if I end up hating you, it's a big success
（ぽえぽえぽえ〜）
(Poe poe poe~)
（どこに隠してんの？）
(Where are you hiding it?)
（まず何が隠されてるんだろう...）
(First, what is being hidden...)
（いぇーい、みってるぅ〜？？）
(Yay, are you watching~??)
（沙花叉クロヱっていうんですね、知らないなぁ）
(She's called Sakamata Chloe, I don't know her)
（踏んで！！）
(Step on me!!)
（><）
(><)
（沙花叉最強！）
(Sakamata is the strongest!)
それじゃダメなというしで　二人になればハッピー
Saying that's no good, being together makes us happy
そのうち二人が嫌で　一人がいいとか言って
Soon being together will be hated, and saying it's better to be alone
どうせなら僕がもう一人　いればなればそれでハッピーだ
If only there were another me, then it would be happy
今日はずっとお陀仏の　返事やってた風みたいさ
Today feels like I've been giving replies that are long dead
このままだと　知りながらも　止められないのさ
Even knowing it will stay like this, I can't stop it
アイマイにしたいのさ　好きでいたって歪んでいく内緒
I want to make it ambiguous, even if I like you, the secret will warp
アイマイにしたいのさ　嫌いになってしまったら成功
I want to make it ambiguous, if I end up hating you, it's a success
バイバイもしたいのさ　僕でいたって楽しくないんだ
I want to say goodbye too, it's not fun being me
大概にしたいのさ　もう　もう　もう　はぁ
I want to put an end to it, already, already, already, haa
あるがままを言えそうにない　どうか探して見せて
It seems I can't say it as it is, please find it and show me
嘘と本音の間　うまく隠しといたんで
Between lies and true feelings, I've hidden it well
あ、急いで移動しなきゃ。
Ah, I have to hurry and move.
はっ、と。え、来てる、来てる、来てる、来てる。
Hup. Eh, they're coming, they're coming, they're coming, they're coming.
あー！ちょっと待って、かっこいい自分...
Ah! Wait a minute, cool self...
あ、ああ、あー。あ、なんだか、うわーすごい！
Ah, ah, ah-. Ah, somehow, wow, amazing!
焼肉屋さんある！え、この後食べに行くか。
There's a yakiniku restaurant! Eh, should I go eat there later?
食べに行きたい。え、え、待って。
I want to go eat. Eh, eh, wait.
なんかレンタルルーム...これ何ですかこれ？
Some kind of rental room... what is this?
これ見ていいやつですか？
Is this okay to look at?
へぇー、完全個室...あ、へぇー。ほう。
Heh, completely private rooms... ah, heh. Ho.
そんなんもあるんですね。へぇー。
They have things like that too. Heh.
あ、あれ？あ、あれ見て！
Ah, wait? Ah, look at that!
なんか、へ？あ、すごい可愛い女の子いる！
Something, eh? Ah, there's a really cute girl!
なにあれ、可愛い、めちゃ可愛い。
What's that, cute, so cute.
「アンコールしてよね？」あ、誰かがライブやってるのかな？
"Won't you do an encore?" Ah, is someone doing a live show?
誰だろうね。これみんなアンコールしたほうがいいんじゃない？さすがに。
I wonder who. Everyone should probably do an encore, right? Seriously.
なんか圧感じるしね。え、これ、これいいよ。
I feel some pressure too. Eh, this, this is good.
え、じゃあちょっとみんな、誰かのライブもしね、見てるんだったら、アンコールしたほうがいいと思います。
Eh, so everyone, if you're watching someone's live show, I think you should do an encore.
この後、無限であったりとか、なんとか、まあ知らないけど。
After this, whether it's Mugen or whatever, well, I don't know.
お邪魔しましたー。行きます。
Sorry for bothering you. I'm going.
はっ、と。
Hup.
ちょっと...もう一回いいっすか？もう一回行くよ。
Wait... can I do it one more time? I'm going again.
Now Loading
笑ってるけどさ、マジふざけんな。大変なんだよ。
You're laughing, but seriously, don't mess around. It's tough.
はっ！
Ha!
あー、ちょっと待って...
Ah, wait a second...
遠心力がね、いや、あー。
The centrifugal force, yeah, ah.
じゃ、最後にバシッと決めてサヨナラしますね。
Well then, I'll finish it off perfectly and say goodbye.
行きますよ！
Here I go!
はっ！
Ha!
おっ...
Oh...
イェーイ！
Yay!
（笑い声）
(Laughing)
丸の内サディスティック
Marunouchi Sadistic
作詞・作曲 椎名林檎
Lyrics/Composition: Shiina Ringo
報酬は入社後並行線で
The reward is parallel lines after joining the company
東京は愛せど何にも無い
Even though I love Tokyo, there is nothing there
リッケン620頂戴
Give me a Ricken 620
19万も持って居ない　御茶ノ水
I don't even have 190,000 yen, Ochanomizu
マーシャルの匂いで飛んじゃって大変さ
Floating away on the scent of Marshalls, it's a disaster
毎晩絶頂に達して居るだけ
Just reaching a climax every night
ラットひとつを商売道具にしてるさ
Using a single RAT as a tool of the trade
そしたらベンジーが肺に映ってトリップ
Then Benjie is reflected in my lungs, and I trip
最近は銀座で警官ごっこ
Lately, playing cop in Ginza
国境は越えても盛者必衰
Even if borders are crossed, the prosperous must decline
領収書を頂戴
Give me the receipt
税理士なんて付いて居ない　後楽園
I don't have a tax accountant, Korakuen
将来僧になって結婚して欲しい
I want you to become a monk in the future and marry me
毎晩寝具で遊戯するだけ
Just playing around in the bedding every night
ピザ屋の彼女になってみたい
I want to try being a pizza shop girl
そしたらベンジー、あたしをグレッチで殴って
Then Benjie, hit me with a Gretsch
青噛んで行って頂戴
Please chew on the blue
終電で帰るってば　池袋
I'll go home on the last train, Ikebukuro
マーシャルの匂いで飛んじゃって大変さ
Floating away on the scent of Marshalls, it's a disaster
毎晩絶頂に達して居るだけ
Just reaching a climax every night
ラットひとつを商売道具にしてるさ
Using a single RAT as a tool of the trade
そしたらベンジーが肺に映ってトリップ
Then Benjie is reflected in my lungs, and I trip
将来僧になって結婚して欲しい
I want you to become a monk in the future and marry me
毎晩寝具で遊戯するだけ
Just playing around in the bedding every night
ピザ屋の彼女になってみたい
I want to try being a pizza shop girl
そしたらベンジー、あたしをグレッチで殴って
Then Benjie, hit me with a Gretsch
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
まだまだライブは続きます！
The live stream is still continuing!
沙花叉この後も頑張るので、
Sakamata will do her best from here on too,
応援よろしくお願いします！
so please support me!
震わせて この心を
Make it tremble, this heart of mine.
思い切り 突き刺して
Pierce right through it.
濡れたままで 知らぬふりは もうやめて
Stop pretending you don't know while staying wet.
暇つぶしには 飽きたのよ
I'm tired of just passing the time.
街中 ビニールの世界を
This world full of vinyl.
お前の 思惑から 無邪気に 抜け出して
Innocently breaking free from your intentions.
さよなら 愛を込めて
Goodbye, with all my love.
気の済むまで 暴れなよ
Go wild until you're satisfied.
甘いだろう ぐちゃぐちゃにするぜ
Isn't it sweet? I'm gonna make a mess of it.
喧騒に上がる 煙に 飛び込んでいくだけさ
I'll just jump into the smoke rising from the bustle.
遊びじゃないのよ あなたには なんて
This isn't a game, as if I'd say that to you.
適当に 言葉 吐き散らして
Just spitting out random words.
喧騒に上がる 煙に 薪をくべろ
Add fuel to the smoke rising from the bustle.
今日も 軽やかなステップで 騙し騙し 生きていこうじゃないか
Let's live through today with light steps and little tricks.
真っ暗な 明日も さら抜いてさ
Pushing through even the darkest tomorrow.
誰に向けた 合図なの
Who are those signals meant for?
何に 突き動かされてる
What is it that's driving you?
苦しいだけの現実は もうやめて
Enough of this painful reality.
さよなら 愛を込めて
Goodbye, with all my love.
息苦しいなよ この街の 余り回るほどの空気を
It's suffocating, the overflowing air of this city.
地べた ビニールの中から ストリートへ抜け出したなら
Once you break out from the vinyl on the ground to the streets.
遊びきるんだ この世界
I'll play this world to the end.
狂騒乱舞に 暴れまわれ
Go wild in a frenzied dance.
重なった もんがちでしょ
The one who stacks up wins, right?
さよなら 愛を込めて お前の丈を 着飾って どんちゃん騒ぎ
Goodbye, with all my love. Dress up in your best and let's party.
前触れも なく さあ
Without any warning, come on.
さよなら 愛を込めて お前の丈を 着飾って 繋いだ
Goodbye, with all my love. Dress up in your best, and hold on...
手は離さないで
...don't let go of my hand.
迷走するのよ この港 爆心地だろ 清々するぜ
I'm going astray. This port is ground zero, how refreshing.
激怒 時の坩堝へ 飛び込んでいくだけさ
Just diving into the melting pot of rage and time.
遊びじゃないのよ あなたとは なんて 嘘で固めた この世なら
This isn't a game, with you... If this world is built on lies...
冗談もご愛嬌でしょ
...even a joke is just part of the charm.
暴れなよ 甘いだろう ぐちゃぐちゃにするぜ
Go wild. Isn't it sweet? I'm gonna make a mess of it.
喧騒に上がる 煙に 飛び込んでいくだけさ
I'll just jump into the smoke rising from the bustle.
遊びきるんだ この世界
I'll play this world to the end.
狂騒乱舞に 暴れまわれ
Go wild in a frenzied dance.
最後の最後には ニカッと 笑って見せる
At the very, very end, I'll show you a big grin.
みんな 今日は 会いに来てくれて ありがとう
Thank you all for coming to see me today.
今日はですね 沙花叉クロヱの 1周年 デビューから 1年 ということで
Today marks Sakamata Chloe's first anniversary, one year since my debut.
まあ 沙花叉が 3Dライブを すること自体が 2回目 なんですけど
Well, this is only the second time that I've done a 3D live performance.
前の時はね、結構お披露目っていうのもあってふざけたりとかね、多くって、
In the past, since it was my 3D debut, there was a lot of fooling around,
あの意味の分からないギャンブルが始まったりとかね、しておりましたが
and nonsensical gambling would start and things like that.
今回はですね、沙花叉クロヱのデビューから1年間の、ま、成長だったりとか、
But this time, it's about my growth over the year since my debut,
ま、沙花叉の活動の結晶みたいなものかなと思うので
and it's like the culmination of everything I've done.
今回はあんまりふざけたりとかしないで真面目にちょっとみんなにお見せできたらなと思って、
So I wanted to show you all a more serious side this time without too much joking around,
たくさんダンスとか歌も練習してきたし
and I've practiced my dancing and singing a lot.
結構ね、このライブの構成自体も考えたりしましたので、
I even thought about the structure of the live concert itself,
みんなもね、あの真面目に…あの真面目に、真面目に、
so I'd be happy if you all... seriously...
見てもらえたら嬉しいなって思います。
watched it seriously.
いや本当にもうあっという間だったなとも思うし、
Wow, I really feel like it's gone by in a flash,
でも沙花叉、なんかまだまだこれから先もやりたいことがいっぱいあるから
but there are still so many things I want to do in the future.
これから先のためにももっともっと前までよりもさらに頑張んなきゃなと思って
For the sake of that future, I felt I had to work even harder than before,
今回このライブに向けて頑張ってきてるから、みんなも楽しみに見てくれてたら嬉しいなと思います。
and I've been working hard for this live, so I hope you all enjoy it.
最後まで見てくれると嬉しいな。
I'd be happy if you watched until the end.
みんな、いつも本当にありがとうね。後半になったらまた色々告知などもあるかもなので、
Thank you all so much, as always. There might be some announcements in the second half,
ぜひぜひ最後まで見てね。
so please, please watch until the very end.
最後まで頑張るよ。真面目に頑張ります。
I'll do my best until the end. I'll work seriously.
トコトコトコトコ…えへへ
Toko-toko-toko-toko... Ehehe.
すごい頑張ったんだけど、どう、どうですか？
I worked really hard, so how was it?
ちょっと運動音痴ながら、あの、たくさんダンスの方やらせていただきまして、
Even though I'm not very athletic, I did a lot of dancing,
あの照れ照れって感じで、あのよしよししてもらえたらなと思うのですが、どうでしょうその辺。
so I'm a bit embarrassed, but I hope you'll give me some headpats.
みんなありがとうね。いやあのね、ストリーミングハートがね、マジで、マジで息が続かないんだよね。本当に。
Thank you all. Seriously, with "Streaming Heart," I really can't catch my breath. I mean it.
めちゃくちゃ好きな曲だし、今回のライブに合うなと思って選ばせていただいたんですが、やっぱね、ダンスしながらが、きつかったし、
It's a song I love, and I chose it because I thought it fit this live, but singing it while dancing was tough.
沙花叉ね、この、この、この動きがマジで苦手すぎて、大変でした。
Sakamata is just really bad at this specific movement, so it was hard.
そしてマイノリティエスケープもね、あの、全編フルでね、あの、踊るっていうね、ちょっと、あの何を頑張ったんだって感じなんですけどそこ。
And for "Minority Escape," I danced the full version, which I worked really hard on.
すごい頑張らせていただきました、そこ。なのでね、もうバテバテだったんですが、そのあとビニールね、行きましたね。
I gave it my all. I was completely exhausted, but then we went into "Vinyl."
ビニールが一番なんか上手くいった気がする。どうでしょうかね。楽しんでくれたかな、みんな。
I feel like "Vinyl" went the best. What do you think? Did you enjoy it, everyone?
で、みんなの応援のコメント見ながらだったからね、ちょっとずつ緊張がほぐれてきました。
Looking at all your supportive comments helped my nerves settle a bit.
では、ここになんですが、水族館にあるものを用意してもらいました。なんだと思う？こちらです！
Now then, I had something you'd find at an aquarium prepared here. What do you think it is? It's this!
真面目にやりますから沙花叉は。よろしくお願いしますね。真面目ですよ皆さん。真面目に見てください。
Sakamata is going to do this seriously. Please bear with me. I'm serious, everyone. Watch seriously.
すげー！滑ってった。よく通ったよねこれ。じゃあちょっとやってみるか。
Wow! It slid right past. That actually worked. Well, let's give it a try.
沙花叉ね、実はね、詳しい内容教えてもらってないんだよねこれ。教えてくれなかったの。行くよ！トゥルン！
Actually, Sakamata wasn't told the details about this. They wouldn't tell me. Here I go! *Spin*
はい！
There!
ほい！
Ho!
はい！あーダメだわ。
Ha! Ah, it's no good.
あ、もう一回。トゥルン！いや、でも通常ステージですね。通常ステージもいいけどね。
Ah, one more time. *Spin* Well, it's the normal stage. Normal stage is fine, though.
あ、お、オーバだ！はい！
Ah, oh, it's an over! There!
え！？助けて！熱い！いやいやいや、え、スイカある？ある？
Eh?! Help! It's hot! No way, wait, is there a watermelon? Is there?
はっ！ま、いっか。さすがにね、そんな初手に当たんないわな。はい！
Hah! Oh well. I guess I wouldn't hit it on the first try. There!
おぉー！え、何これ何これ？え、熱そう熱そう！はい！
Whoa! Eh, what's this? What's this? Whoa, looks intense! There!
うわ、怖い怖い怖い！何だこの仮面って何なんだろうこれ。はい！
Whoa, scary scary! What's with this mask? What even is this? There!
あ、リプレイ！はい！
Ah, replay! There!
あー…どうなんでしょうね。こっから上手くいくんでしょうか。
Ah... I wonder. Will things go well from here?
これあれだね、なんかさ、強い目もわかんないね。
With this, I can't even tell which symbols are strong.
ね、みんな助けて！全然当たんない！トゥルン！
Help me, everyone! I'm not hitting anything! *Spin*
はい！あ、待って待って、チェリーチェリーで、あ！
There! Ah, wait, wait, cherries, cherries, and... ah!
はい！あ、みんながいる！みんながいるよ！あ！
There! Oh, everyone's there! Everyone's there! Ah!
来た緑来た緑来た！熱い熱い！みんな、みんな行くぞ！はっ！
Green came! Green came! This is intense! Everyone, let's go! Hah!
来たー！
It's here!
ゴー、ゴー、ゴー。
Go, go, go.
お、来たじゃん。これ。
Oh, it came! This.
チェリー来た、チェリー。揃ったよ。
Cherries came, cherries. They matched.
これありますね。緑に発展させなきゃ。
This is it. I have to evolve it to green.
トゥルン。
*Sound effect*
え、何これ、何これ、何これ？
Eh, what's this, what's this, what's this?
え、入ったんだけど。え、はい。
Eh, it went in. Eh, yes.
いやマジで、当たる、絶対当たる。
No really, I'll win, definitely win.
さっきみんなが、みんながたくさん、
Just now, everyone, everyone sent so many
スパチャ送ってくれたから虹色になったから当ててください、
あの、虹色なってるはずなんで。
super chats that it turned rainbow colored, so please
let me win, um, it should be rainbow colored.
はい！
Yes!
お！ ああー！
Oh! Aah!
やばいやばいやばい！
This is bad, bad, bad!
嘘。こんなこともあったよね。
No way. Things like this happened too.
これが観たかったんでしょう？ ジュッ、ジュッ、ジュッ。
This is what you wanted to see, right? *Sizzle*
言われながら恥ずかしいんですが。トゥルン。
It's embarrassing being told that. *Sound effect*
これは、あ、でももしかしたら、これ当たり目次第では...
This is, ah, but maybe, depending on the winning line...
あ、熱くなってきた？ 熱くなってきそう。
Ah, is it getting hot? It feels like it's getting hot.
バ、バ、バ、バ、バ... 当たる当たる当たる。
Ba, ba, ba, ba, ba... I'll win, I'll win, I'll win.
はい！
Yes!
お！ おお。
Oh! Ooh.
やばい。
This is bad.
これは来ますね。チャンス目かな。
This is coming. Is it a chance line?
いきましょう。
Let's go.
赤に発展した、みんな。みんな！
It evolved to red, everyone. Everyone!
なななな、な。ゾロ目、当たる気満々じゃ。はい、トゥルン。
Se-se-se-se, seven. Triple digits, I'm so ready to win. Yes.
あー、なんだ。ハズレかと思ったら。
Ah, what. I thought I lost.
え、え、え、え、えー！ そんな...
Eh, eh, eh, eh, ehh! Such a...
え、直当たり、もしかして？ 直ビック？
Eh, a direct win, maybe? A direct big win?
え、え、これ来ちゃうのか？ 来ちゃうのか？
Eh, eh, is this coming? Is it coming?
これビックじゃないの？ 行くよ、行くよ、せーの！
Isn't this a big win? I'm going, I'm going, one-two-!
お！ ああー！
Oh! Aah!
ビックボーナス！
Big Bonus!
え、何これ、何これ？
Eh, what is this, what is this?
え、マジで知らないんだよね、沙花叉は。何も。
Eh, Sakamata really doesn't know. Anything.
ultra soul
おおー！
Ooh!
やったー、みんな！ ビックボーナスだ、ありがとう！
We did it, everyone! It's a Big Bonus, thank you!
どれだけがんばりゃいい
How hard should I work?
誰かのためなの
Is it for someone's sake?
分かっているのに
Even though I know
思いは揺らぐ
My thoughts waver
結末ばかりに気を取られ
Distracted only by the outcome
この瞬間(とき)を楽しめない メマイ
I can't enjoy this moment, dizzy
夢じゃないあれもこれも
It's not a dream, that or this
その手でドアをあけましょう
Let's open the door with those hands
祝福が欲しいのなら
If you want a blessing
悲しみをしり独りで 泣きましょう
Know sadness and weep alone
そして輝くウルトラソウル
And then, the shining Ultra Soul
ハイ！
Hi!
きたー！ ビックジャッジ！
It's here! Big Judge!
己の限界に
To your own limits
気づいたつもりかい
Do you think you've noticed them?
かすり傷さえも
Even a scratch
無いまま終わりそう
Seems like it'll end without one
一番大事な人がほら
Look, the most important person
いつでもあなたを見てるんやって
Is always looking at you, they say
夢じゃないあれもこれも
It's not a dream, that or this
今こそ胸をはりましょう
Now is the time to stand proud
祝福が欲しいのなら
If you want a blessing
底なしのペイン 迎えてあげましょう
Let's welcome the bottomless pain
そして戦うウルトラソウル
And then, the fighting Ultra Soul
ハイ！
Hi!
やったー！ とどめあるんじゃない？
We did it! Is there a finishing move?
行くぞー！
Let's go!
やったー！
We did it!
希望と失望に遊ばれ
Toyed with by hope and despair
鍛え抜かれる Do it, do it, do it, do it
Tempered by it, Do it, do it, do it, do it
夢じゃないあれもこれも
It's not a dream, that or this
今こそ胸をはりましょう
Now is the time to stand proud
祝福が欲しいのなら
If you want a blessing
歓びを知りパーっと 暴れましょう
Know joy and run wild with a bang
ホントだらけ あれもこれも
Full of truth, that or this
つかんだら放しちゃいけない
Once you grab it, don't let go
祝福が欲しいのなら
If you want a blessing
そして羽ばたくウルトラソウル
And then, the soaring Ultra Soul
やったー！ まだまだ残ってんだ！
We did it! There's still more left!
やったー！
We did it!
ウルトラソウル！
Ultra Soul!
ハイ！
Hi!
traveling
作詞・作曲 宇多田ヒカル
Lyrics & Composition: Hikaru Utada
Tcha-cha-cha... Tcha-cha-cha...
仕事にも精が出る
Diligence in work as well
金曜の午後
Friday afternoon
タクシーもすぐつかまる
A taxi is easily caught
目指すは君
Destination is you
「どちらまで行かれます?」
“Where are you heading to?”
「ちょっとそこまで」
“Just over there”
「不景気で困ります」
“Recession is a bother”
「ドアに注意」
“Watch the door”
風にまたぎ月へ登り
Straddling the wind, climbing to the moon
僕の席は君の隣
My seat is next to yours
ふいに我に返りくらり
Suddenly returning to my senses, dizzy
春の夜の夢のごとし
Like a dream on a spring night
Traveling 君を乗せて
Traveling, carrying you along
アスファルトを照らし
Illuminating the asphalt
Traveling どこへ行くの?
Traveling, where are we going?
遠くならどこへでも
Anywhere, if it's far
Traveling もっと揺らして
Traveling, shake it more
壊したくなる衝動
An impulse to break things
Traveling もっと飛ばして
Traveling, fly faster
急ぐことはないけど
There's no need to hurry, but
Tcha-cha-cha... Tcha-cha-cha...
聞かせたい歌がある
There's a song I want you to hear
エンドレスリピート
Endless repeat
気持ちに拍車かかる
Acceleration of feelings
狙い通り
Just as aimed
波とはしゃぎ雲を誘い
Frolicking with waves, inviting the clouds
ついに僕は君に出会い
Finally, I met you
若さ故にすぐに知なり
Because of youth, quickly becoming intimate
風の前の塵に同じ
Same as dust before the wind
Traveling 胸を寄せて
Traveling, drawing chests close
いつもより目立っちゃおう
Let's stand out more than usual
Traveling ここは嫌よ
Traveling, I don't like it here
目的地はまだだよ
The destination isn't yet
Traveling 窓を下げて
Traveling, lower the window
何も怖くないモード
No-fear-at-all mode
Traveling ここでいいよ
Traveling, here is fine
全ては気分次第
Everything is up to the mood
みんな踊り出す時間だ
Time for everyone to start dancing
待ちきれず今夜
Can't wait for tonight
隠してた願いが疼きます
The hidden wish aches
みんな盛り上がる時間だ
Time for everyone to get excited
どうしてだろうか
I wonder why
少しだけ不安が残ります
A little anxiety remains
Traveling 君を乗せて
Traveling, carrying you along
アスファルトを照らし
Illuminating the asphalt
Traveling どこにいるの?
Traveling, where are you?
これからがいいところ
The best part is from now on
Traveling もっと揺らして
Traveling, shake it more
壊したくなる衝動
An impulse to break things
Traveling もっと飛ばして
Traveling, fly faster
止まるのが怖い ちょっと
Afraid of stopping, a little
はーい、みんなー！
Hi, everyone!
ちょっと、あの、沙花叉ね、スロットあんなのって知らなかったんですが、
I didn't know the slot machine part would be like that,
めちゃくちゃ面白かった！ありがとう！
but it was so much fun! Thank you!
みんなのゾロ目も届いてたしね、
I saw all of your matching numbers too.
みんなのね、スパチャとかコメントとか、Twitterのハッシュタグとか、
Thanks to your Super Chats, comments, and Twitter hashtags,
そのおかげで当たったのかもしれない...分からないですけど。
maybe that's why I won... I don't know for sure though.
ありがとうございます！ウルトラソウル！
Thank you very much! Ultra Soul!
沙花叉、もうこれやりたくてさ、もはや名刺のスタンプ追加したまである。
I wanted to do this so badly, I even added a stamp to my business card.
ウルトラソウル、ハイ！がやりたかった。
I really wanted to shout, "Ultra Soul, Hey!"
ちょっとカメラマンさんのこと殴らせて頂きましたけれども、ありがとうございます。
I kind of hit the cameraman there, but thank you.
「トラベリング」をですね、ちょっと沙花叉、今回のグッズにね、
"Traveling" is actually related to the merch I'm releasing this time,
あの、関係してるので、ここでグッズ紹介なんてさせて頂いちゃってもよろしいでしょうか？だめ？
so would it be alright if I introduced some of it here? No?
はい！ということで、「トラベリング」でいっぱい旅をしてきたということで、
Okay! Since we've done a lot of traveling with "Traveling,"
今回のグッズはこちら！ジャジャン！
here is this time's merchandise! Ta-da!
沙花叉クロヱ 活動1周年記念
Sakamata Chloe 1st Anniversary
テーマは「旅行」です。沙花叉は飼育員さんと一緒に、
The theme is "Travel." I want to go to lots of different places
たくさん色々なところに行きたいと思いまして、今回のグッズを考えました。
together with all of you keepers, so I came up with these items.
キービジュアルは、温泉街・風呂上がり沙花叉です。
The key visual is Sakamata after a bath in a hot spring town.
「あ、お風呂入ったんだ」ってね。天才パパセリが今回もやってくれました！
Like, "Oh, she took a bath." My genius Papa Paseri did it again!
まずは、こちら！
First up is this!
B2タペストリー
B2 Tapestry
はい。こちらですね。タペストリーになっていますので、飾ってほしい。
Yes, this one. It's a tapestry, so please hang it up.
いや、マジで、このおっぱいですよね、やっぱりね。おっぱいが素晴らしかったり、
I mean, seriously, look at these breasts. They're amazing,
なんか太もももすごいギリギリまで見えちゃったりなんかして。エッチだなって思います。飾ってください。
and you can see her thighs right up to the limit. I think it's sexy. Please display it.
続いては、こちら！
Next is this!
万年カレンダー
Perpetual Calendar
はい。万年カレンダー！
Yes, a perpetual calendar!
旅行や沙花叉の配信ごとに、1個目のこの左端のキューブを好きなデザインにしたりしてほしいです。
I want you to change the leftmost cube to a design you like for travels or my streams.
沙花叉は机の上に飾ります。あの、最近は机きれいなんで。うーん、まあまあ、はい。
I'll display mine on my desk. My desk is clean lately, so... yeah.
続いて、こちら！
Next is this!
トラベルポーチ
Travel Pouch
はい。トラベルポーチ！普段使いをするなら、カバンの中に入れたりとか、
Yes, a travel pouch! For everyday use, you can put it in your bag,
モバイルバッテリーとか入れてほしいなって。あと女の子とかもね、お化粧品とか小物を入れてほしいななんて思います。
or use it for mobile batteries. Girls can use it for cosmetics and small items too.
旅行に行く時とかはね、あのお風呂に行く用の、小さいポーチみたいな感じで持ってったら、
When traveling, it's perfect as a small pouch for going to the bath,
なんかいいんじゃないかなーなんて思って、頑張って作りましたので。ちっちゃい沙花叉も実はいるよ。
I thought that would be nice, so I worked hard on it. There's even a tiny Sakamata on it.
いるよ。え、なに？
She's there. Eh, what?
あ、お風呂？あ、風呂入りじゃないんですけど。はぁ？風呂入ってますけど！
Oh, the bath? I'm not avoiding baths. What? I do take baths!
え、今日、お風呂入ってきましたよ、さすがに。沙花叉、汗もかきますしね。ね？みんな？ね？
I took a bath today, obviously. Even I sweat, you know. Right, everyone? Right?
そうだよね、そうだよね。カメラマンさん、すごい今、顔伏せてる。え、え、え、臭い？大丈夫？
Exactly, exactly. The cameraman is looking away... Wait, do I smell? Am I okay?
え、大丈夫？その反応気になるんだけど大丈夫？入ってきましたよね？
Are you sure? I'm worried by that reaction. I did take a bath, right?
ああ、すごいゆっくり、こう「あ、はい」みたいに頷いて頂きました。ありがとうございます。
Ah, he gave me a very slow, reluctant nod. Thank you.
はい。沙花叉はね、旅行中しっかりとお風呂に入る派ですから。
Yes, I'm the type who definitely takes baths while traveling.
そして、こちら！
And next is this!
沙花叉クロヱぬいぐるみ
Sakamata Chloe Plushie
沙花叉ぬいぐるみ！これめちゃくちゃいいよ！
The Sakamata plushie! This is really great!
こちらめちゃくちゃ細部にこだわりました。可愛いでしょ、これ。超可愛いからこれ、本当に。
I was super picky about the details. Isn't it cute? It's really, really cute.
フード着脱可能だったりね、細かい装飾を頑張って再現しましたので、旅行に行く時に一緒に沙花叉を連れて行ってほしいです。
The hood is removable, and we worked hard on the small decorations. Please take Sakamata with you on your travels.
商品到着後に、ぬいぐるみを使ったフォトコンテスト企画も考えてますので、よろしくお願いします。
I'm also planning a photo contest using the plushies after they arrive, so look forward to that.
沙花叉はベッドの横に飾って、たまに抱きしめたりして使おうと思ってるので、2個買いました。
I'll keep mine next to my bed and hug it sometimes, so I bought two for myself.
あと、シチュエーションボイスがあるんですよ。
Also, there's a situation voice.
こちらは温泉街で飼育員さんとデートしている感じなので、一緒にデートしよう、みたいな感じです。
This one is like a date with a keeper in a hot spring town. It's like, "Let's go on a date."
全部セット特典は、なんと直筆メッセージポストカードと特典ボイスが付きます！
The full set bonus includes a postcard with a handwritten message and a bonus voice!
活動1周年記念 フルセット購入特典
1st Anniversary Activity Full Set Purchase Bonus
今回もね、ポストカードは沙花叉メッセージを直筆で書かせて頂きたいと思います。
For the postcard, I'll be writing the message by hand again this time.
なんかね、多分なんですけど3種類くらい書こうかなと思ってるので、ちゃんと読んでください。
I'm thinking of writing about three different versions, so please make sure to read them.
沙花叉はちゃんと書くので、皆さん読んでください。解読班はいりません。読んでください。
I'll write them properly, so please read them. No decoding team needed. Just read it.
特典ボイスは「のぼせちゃった沙花叉」なので、開放してもらえたらなと思います。
The bonus voice is "Overheated Sakamata," so I hope you'll unlock it.
あの、本当にお風呂苦手なんです。はい。
Um, I'm really not good with baths. Yes.
続いて、次でね、最後の曲になるんですが...
Moving on, the next one will be the last song...
今日で坂又がデビューして1年が経つということで、
Since today marks one year since Sakamata's debut,
あの初配信からもう1年なんですが、
it's already been a year since that first stream.
まあみんなにはね、1年間坂又を見てもらったりとかしたと思うので、
Well, I think everyone's been watching me for a year, so...
ちょっと、いろんな応援してきてくれた飼育員さんたちに、
to all the keepers who've supported me in various ways,
感謝の気持ちなど書いてきたの、見てほしいななんて、
I've written down my feelings of gratitude,
聞いてほしいななんて思います。
and I'd like you to see them, or rather, listen.
じゃあ行くよ。
Okay, here I go.
みんな、今日は坂又の1周年ライブに来てくれてありがとう。
Everyone, thank you for coming to my 1st anniversary live today.
決して順調とは言えない1年で、
It's been a year that was by no means smooth,
みんなにたくさん心配かけちゃって、ごめんね。
and I'm sorry for causing you all so much worry.
今こうして元気に毎日楽しく活動できているのは、
The reason I'm able to be active and have fun every day like this now is
応援してくれるみんなの言葉があったからです。本当だよ。
because of the words of support from everyone. It's true.
いつも坂又を支えてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for always supporting Sakamata.
まだまだ坂又の活動は始まったばかり。
Sakamata's activities have only just begun.
全力で頑張って、みんなとの日々を楽しんでいくので、
I'll do my best and enjoy the days with everyone,
これからの坂又を見てください。
so please keep an eye on Sakamata from now on.
そしてよければ、坂又のそばにいてください。
And if you don't mind, please stay by Sakamata's side.
いつもありがとう。
Thank you always.
大好きだよ。
I love you.
はい。ありがとうございました。
Yes. Thank you very much.
あぶなあぶな、泣いちゃうとこ。あぶなあぶな。
Phew, phew, almost cried there. Phew.
はいお？お？もこもこ？え？
Yes-oh? Oh? Fluffy? Huh?
あれ？このもこもこはもしや？
Huh? Is this fluffiness perhaps...?
これってもしかして、もしかして、
Could this be, perhaps, could it be...
わ、どんどんもこもこしてきてんじゃん。
Whoa, it's getting fluffier and fluffier.
わあわあわあすごいすごいすごい！
Whoa, whoa, whoa, amazing, amazing, amazing!
すごい！なんだこれ！うわああ！
Amazing! What is this! Waaaah!
なんか微妙に透けてる、や、見ないで、見ないで。
It's slightly transparent, no, don't look, don't look.
では、聞いてください。Story。
Now, please listen. Story.
Story
作詞：AI 作曲：2SOUL for 2SOUL MUSIC, INC.
Lyrics: AI / Composition: 2SOUL for 2SOUL MUSIC, INC.
限られた時の中で
Within the limited time
どれだけのコトが出来るのだろう...
How many things can I do...
言葉にならないほどの思いを
The feelings that are beyond words
どれだけアナタに伝えられるだろう...
How much can I convey to you...
ずっと閉じ込めてた 胸の痛みを消してくれた
You erased the pain in my chest that I'd kept locked away for so long
今私が笑えるのは
The reason I can smile now is
一緒に泣いてくれたキミがいたから
Because you were there to cry with me
一人じゃないから キミが私を守るから
Because I'm not alone, because you protect me
強くなれる もう何も怖くないヨ...
I can become strong, I'm not afraid of anything anymore...
時がなだめてく 痛みと共に流れてく
Time soothes it, it flows away along with the pain
日の光がやさしく照らしてくれる
The sunlight shines gently on me
説明する言葉も
Even the words to explain
むりして笑うコトもしなくていいから
You don't even have to force a smile
何かあるなら いつでも頼ってほしい
If anything happens, I want you to rely on me anytime
疲れた時は 肩をかすから
When you're tired, I'll lend you my shoulder.
どんなに強がっても
No matter how much you try to be strong,
ため息くらいする時もある
there are times you might let out a sigh.
孤独じゃ重い扉も
Even a door that is too heavy to open alone,
共に立ち上がればまた動き始める
if we stand up together, it will start to move again.
一人じゃないから 私がキミを守るから
You're not alone, because I'll be there to protect you.
あなたの笑う顔が見たいと思うから
Because I want to see your smiling face.
時がなだめてく 痛みと共に流れてく
Time will soothe the pain as it flows away.
日の光がやさしく照らしてくれる
The sunlight will gently shine upon you.
時には人は傷付き、傷付けながら
Sometimes people get hurt, and hurt others,
染まる色はそれぞれ違うけど
and we all turn out different colors.
自分だけのStory 作りながら生きてくの
But we keep living, creating our own unique story.
だからずっと ずっと あきらめないで
So please, don't ever, ever give up.
一人じゃないから 私がキミを守るから
You're not alone, because I'll be there to protect you.
あなたの笑う顔が見たいと思うから
Because I want to see your smiling face.
時がなだめてく 痛みと共に流れてく
Time will soothe the pain as it flows away.
日の光がやさしく照らしてくれる
The sunlight will gently shine upon you.